[
    {
        "question": "Former Director General of Confederation of Indian Industry (CII) Tarun Das was recently awarded the Honorary Citizen Award of which country?",
        "options": [
            "Sri Lanka ",
            "Maldives ",
            "Singapore ",
            "Malaysia "
        ],
        "answer": "Singapore ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "India has signed a deal with which country for export of BrahMos supersonic cruise missiles?",
        "options": [
            "Mauritius  ",
            "Bangladesh ",
            "Ukraine ",
            "Indonesia "
        ],
        "answer": "Indonesia ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the main objective of Exercise Devil Strike conducted by the Indian Army?",
        "options": [
            "To test new technologies ",
            "To enhance combat readiness and operational capabilities ",
            "To expand international military alliances ",
            "To conduct humanitarian assistance missions "
        ],
        "answer": "To enhance combat readiness and operational capabilities ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was the peace agreement between Israel and the militant Palestinian group Hamas signed in January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Abu Dhabi, UAE  ",
            "Riyadh, Saudi Arabia  ",
            "Manama, Bahrain  ",
            "Doha, Qatar "
        ],
        "answer": "Doha, Qatar ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which countries are the guarantors of the recently signed peace deal between Israel and Palestinian group Hamas?",
        "options": [
            "Qatar, Egypt, and USA  ",
            "Kuwait, Malaysia and USA ",
            "Russia, Japan and China ",
            "India, Russia and USA "
        ],
        "answer": "Qatar, Egypt, and USA  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many agreements/MoUs were signed between India and Spain during the Minister for External Affairs Dr. Jaishankar\u2019s visit to Spain in January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "three  ",
            "two  ",
            "six  ",
            "four "
        ],
        "answer": "two  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding ISRO\u2019s Third Launch Pad:  1. It will be established at Satish Dhawan Space Centre of Indian Space Research Organisation (ISRO) at Sriharikota, Andhra Pradesh.  2. It will be configured for the next generation launch vehicles of ISRO.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "Both 1 and 2 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where will the third launch pad of the Indian Space Research Organisation be constructed?",
        "options": [
            "Liquid Propulsion Systems Centre in Mahendragiri, Tamil Nadu ",
            "Dr Abdul Kalam Island in Bhadrak, Odisha  ",
            "Vikram Sarabhai Space Centre in Thiruvananthapuram, Kerala ",
            "Satish Dhawan Space Centre in Sriharikota, Andhra Pradesh "
        ],
        "answer": "Satish Dhawan Space Centre in Sriharikota, Andhra Pradesh ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the budget for the proposed third launch pad of the Indian Space Research Organisation?",
        "options": [
            "Rs 4123.95 crore ",
            "Rs 3984.86 crore ",
            "Rs 2719.53 crore ",
            "Rs 5178.11 crore "
        ],
        "answer": "Rs 3984.86 crore ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Small Finance Bank has introduced two new slabs introduced are for balances between \u20b910 lakhs and \u20b925 lakhs and \u20b925 lakhs to \u20b91 crore for savings bank (SB) deposit holders?",
        "options": [
            "deposit holders? ",
            "Utkarsh Small Finance Bank  ",
            "AU Small Finance Bank ",
            "Ujjivan Small Finance Bank ",
            "Equitas Small Finance Bank "
        ],
        "answer": "Ujjivan Small Finance Bank ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding the Bharat Ranbhoomi Darshan App:  1. It is aimed at promoting connectivity, tourism, and socio-economic development in border regions.  2. It is developed by the Ministry of Defence in collaboration with the Ministry of Tourism.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "Both 1 and 2 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been reappointed as the Chairperson of the Executive Council of the Prime Ministers Museum and Library Society?",
        "options": [
            "Utpal Kumar Singh ",
            "T. V. Somanathan ",
            "Nripendra Mishra ",
            "Vandana Gurnani "
        ],
        "answer": "Nripendra Mishra ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the term of the newly appointed Chairperson and members of the Executive Council of the Prime Ministers Museum and Library Society?",
        "options": [
            "4 years ",
            "3 years  ",
            "5 years  ",
            "2 years "
        ],
        "answer": "5 years  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which ministry of the government of India comes the Prime Minister Museum and Library?",
        "options": [
            "Ministry of Home Affairs ",
            "Ministry of Culture ",
            "Ministry of Education ",
            "Ministry of Tourism "
        ],
        "answer": "Ministry of Culture ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who will be the chief guest of the 77th Republic Day 2025 celebrations?",
        "options": [
            "Emmanuel Macron ",
            "Abdel Fattah-al Sisi ",
            "Prabowo Subianto ",
            "Joe Biden "
        ],
        "answer": "Prabowo Subianto ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first person to be the chief guest of the Republic Day celebration in India?",
        "options": [
            "Sukarno ",
            "Aung San Suu Kyi ",
            "Queen Elizabeth II ",
            "Rana Abdul Hamid "
        ],
        "answer": "Sukarno ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ministry of the government of India invites foreign leaders to be the chief guest at the Republic Day celebrations?",
        "options": [
            "Ministry of Defence ",
            "Prime Minister of India ",
            "Ministry of Home Affairs ",
            "Ministry of External Affairs "
        ],
        "answer": "Ministry of External Affairs ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ministry of the government of India is responsible for the Republic Day celebration in New Delhi?",
        "options": [
            "Ministry of Defence ",
            "Ministry of Commerce and Industry ",
            "Ministry of Education ",
            "Ministry of External Affairs "
        ],
        "answer": "Ministry of Defence ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which small finance bank has partnered with Tata Digital to offer fixed deposits on the Tata Neu platform?",
        "options": [
            "Capital Small Finance Bank ",
            "North East Small Finance Bank ",
            "Jana Small Finance Bank ",
            "Suryoday Small Finance Bank "
        ],
        "answer": "Suryoday Small Finance Bank ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the author of the book titled \u201cMiddle Class India: Driving Change in the 21st Century\u201d?",
        "options": [
            "Ghazal Alagh  ",
            "Manisha Pande ",
            "Anil Agarwal ",
            "Tilak Mehta "
        ],
        "answer": "Manisha Pande ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the first orbital rocket launched by Jeff Bezos\u2019s company Blue Origin?",
        "options": [
            "New Glenn ",
            "New Shepard ",
            "Atlas V ",
            "Falcon Heavy "
        ],
        "answer": "New Glenn ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the group CEO of Angel One?",
        "options": [
            "Ambarish Kenghe ",
            "Vneet Jaain ",
            "Sanjiv Bajaj ",
            "Siddhartha Lal "
        ],
        "answer": "Ambarish Kenghe ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the Chairman of the reconstituted Atomic Energy Commission (AEC)?",
        "options": [
            "? ",
            "T V Somanathan ",
            "Manoj Govil ",
            "Ajit Kumar Mohanty ",
            "Pankaj Kumar Mishra "
        ],
        "answer": "Manoj Govil ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cabo Verde, an archipelago recently in news, is located in:",
        "options": [
            "Arctic Ocean ",
            "Pacific Ocean ",
            "Indian Ocean ",
            "Atlantic Ocean "
        ],
        "answer": "Atlantic Ocean ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is hosting the 2nd ICC U-19 Women\u2019s T20 World Cup 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Malaysia  ",
            "Australia  ",
            "Sri Lanka  ",
            "UAE "
        ],
        "answer": "Malaysia  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who inaugurated the 2nd Bharat Mobility Global Expo 2025 ?",
        "options": [
            "Amit Shah  ",
            "Rajnath Singh  ",
            "Chirag Paswan  ",
            "Narendra Modi "
        ],
        "answer": "Narendra Modi ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is the largest manufacturer of 3-Wheeler and Tractors in the world?",
        "options": [
            "China ",
            "India ",
            "Russia  ",
            "United States "
        ],
        "answer": "India ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding Prime Minister\u2019s Wi-Fi Access Network Interface (PM-WANI) Scheme:  1. The primary objective is to provide free internet access to all citizens.  2. It encourages local shops and establishments to provide Wi-Fi for last-mile internet delivery.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "2 only ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is National Startup Day celebrated in India?",
        "options": [
            "14th January ",
            "15th January ",
            "16th January ",
            "17th January "
        ],
        "answer": "16th January ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which entity has inked an agreement with Japan Bank for International Cooperation (JBIC) for 120 billion Japanese yen loan facility?",
        "options": [
            "for 120 ",
            "PFC ",
            "NTPC  ",
            "GAIL ",
            "BHEL "
        ],
        "answer": "for 120 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Gibbon wildlife sanctuary is located in which state?",
        "options": [
            "Odisha  ",
            "Assam ",
            "Madhya Pradesh  ",
            "Karnataka "
        ],
        "answer": "Assam ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ashok Chandra has been appointed as the  Managing Director (MD) and Chief Executive Officer (CEO) of which bank?",
        "options": [
            "and Chief Executive Officer ",
            "Punjab National Bank  ",
            "Kotak Mahindra Bank  ",
            "Indian Overseas Bank  ",
            "Canara Bank "
        ],
        "answer": "and Chief Executive Officer ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the MD & CEO of Indian Bank?",
        "options": [
            "Shanti Lal Jain ",
            "Binod Kumar ",
            "Vijay Singh  ",
            "Manoj Yadav "
        ],
        "answer": "Binod Kumar ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Exercise LA PEROUSE, recently in news, is a:",
        "options": [
            "bilateral army exercise ",
            "multinational air force exercise ",
            "patrolling exercise ",
            "multinational naval exercise "
        ],
        "answer": "multinational naval exercise ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    }
]